[
  {
    "id": 3401,
    "question": "aparecen",
    "questionDetails": "Los vampiros aparecen solo de noche.",
    "answer": "appear, listed, displayed",
    "answerDetails": "Vampires appear only night."
  },
  {
    "id": 3402,
    "question": "pares",
    "questionDetails": "Ayer ella dejó dos pares de zapatos bajo la silla.",
    "answer": "pairs, peers, torques",
    "answerDetails": "Yesterday she left two pairs of shoes under the chair."
  },
  {
    "id": 3403,
    "question": "práctica",
    "questionDetails": "La teoría es sencilla. Es otra cosa llevarla a la práctica.",
    "answer": "practice",
    "answerDetails": "The theory is easy. Putting it into practice is another matter."
  },
  {
    "id": 3404,
    "question": "podrán",
    "questionDetails": "Los niños podrán jugar aquí dentro todos los días.",
    "answer": "can",
    "answerDetails": "The children can play in here every day."
  },
  {
    "id": 3405,
    "question": "clima",
    "questionDetails": "En esta compañía nuestra meta es establecer un clima de confianza.",
    "answer": "climate, weather, atmosphere",
    "answerDetails": "At this company our aim is to build a climate of trust."
  },
  {
    "id": 3406,
    "question": "origen",
    "questionDetails": "Su teoría del origen de la vida.",
    "answer": "origin",
    "answerDetails": "His theory of the origin of life."
  },
  {
    "id": 3407,
    "question": "rápida",
    "questionDetails": "Tenía planeada una rápida cremación.",
    "answer": "quick, fast, rapid",
    "answerDetails": "Had a quick cremation all planned."
  },
  {
    "id": 3408,
    "question": "existencia",
    "questionDetails": "Pero tenéis que guardar en secreto nuestra existencia.",
    "answer": "existence",
    "answerDetails": "But you have to keep our existence secret."
  },
  {
    "id": 3409,
    "question": "preguntaba",
    "questionDetails": "Cada año en la escuela religiosa, preguntaba cómo Dios podía dejar que la humanidad sufra.",
    "answer": "i asked",
    "answerDetails": "Every year in religious school, I asked how God could allow suffering."
  },
  {
    "id": 3410,
    "question": "vení",
    "questionDetails": "Vení a buscarla si querés.",
    "answer": "come",
    "answerDetails": "Come and get her if you want her."
  },
  {
    "id": 3411,
    "question": "santiago",
    "questionDetails": "Mis padres me iban a llamar Santiago, pero escogieron Juan en vez.",
    "answer": "james",
    "answerDetails": "My parents were going to name me James, but chose John instead."
  },
  {
    "id": 3412,
    "question": "compadre",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero un hot dog con todo, compadre.",
    "answer": "bro",
    "answerDetails": "I’ll take a hot dog with everything, bro."
  },
  {
    "id": 3413,
    "question": "regrese",
    "answer": "he comes back"
  },
  {
    "id": 3414,
    "question": "semejante",
    "questionDetails": "La calidad es semejante a la que encontrarías en otros sitios.",
    "answer": "similar, such, akin",
    "answerDetails": "The quality is similar to what you might find at other places."
  },
  {
    "id": 3415,
    "question": "presentación",
    "questionDetails": "La presentación de Fernanda sobre los hombres lobo fue muy informativa.",
    "answer": "presentation, submission, filing",
    "answerDetails": "Fernanda’s presentation on werewolves was very informative."
  },
  {
    "id": 3416,
    "question": "quédese",
    "questionDetails": "Quédese junto a mí y lo haremos juntos.",
    "answer": "stay, stick around",
    "answerDetails": "Stay by me and we’ll take it together."
  },
  {
    "id": 3417,
    "question": "enojada",
    "questionDetails": "Estaba enojada con mi papá una noche antes.",
    "answer": "angry, mad, upset",
    "answerDetails": "She was angry with my dad the night before."
  },
  {
    "id": 3418,
    "question": "solita",
    "questionDetails": "Mírate, aquí, toda solita.",
    "answer": "alone",
    "answerDetails": "Look at you all alone in here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3419,
    "question": "embarazo",
    "questionDetails": "Fumar durante el embarazo aumenta las probabilidades de un parto prematuro.",
    "answer": "pregnancy",
    "answerDetails": "Smoking during pregnancy increases the chances of a preterm delivery."
  },
  {
    "id": 3420,
    "question": "sintiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Ya debería estar sintiendo algo.",
    "answer": "feeling, sensing, feelin’",
    "answerDetails": "She should be feeling something by now."
  },
  {
    "id": 3421,
    "question": "divorcio",
    "questionDetails": "Emprender los trámites de divorcio (contra alguien).",
    "answer": "divorce",
    "answerDetails": "To start divorce proceedings (against somebody)."
  },
  {
    "id": 3422,
    "question": "feria",
    "questionDetails": "Necesitamos preparar nuestro material para la feria comercial.",
    "answer": "fair, exhibition",
    "answerDetails": "We need to prepare our materials for the trade fair."
  },
  {
    "id": 3423,
    "question": "déjenme",
    "questionDetails": "Entonces déjenme incrementar la temperatura.",
    "answer": "let me",
    "answerDetails": "So now let me increase the temperature."
  },
  {
    "id": 3424,
    "question": "delincuentes",
    "questionDetails": "Trabaja con delincuentes juveniles.",
    "answer": "offenders, criminals, delinquents",
    "answerDetails": "He works with juvenile offenders."
  },
  {
    "id": 3425,
    "question": "jefes",
    "questionDetails": "Estamos robando a nuestros propios jefes.",
    "answer": "chiefs, bosses, heads",
    "answerDetails": "We are stealing from our own chiefs."
  },
  {
    "id": 3426,
    "question": "miserable",
    "questionDetails": "Después de la muerte de sus hijos, su miserable existencia se volvió casi insoportable.",
    "answer": "wretched, paltry",
    "answerDetails": "After the death of his children, his wretched existence became almost unbearable."
  },
  {
    "id": 3427,
    "question": "entrego",
    "questionDetails": "Me entrego a usted.",
    "answer": "give",
    "answerDetails": "I give you myself."
  },
  {
    "id": 3428,
    "question": "quisiste",
    "questionDetails": "Realmente nunca quisiste que ganara.",
    "answer": "wanted",
    "answerDetails": "You never really wanted me to win."
  },
  {
    "id": 3429,
    "question": "ocupo",
    "questionDetails": "Yo me ocupo de todo aquí.",
    "answer": "take care",
    "answerDetails": "I take care of everything around here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3430,
    "question": "iré",
    "questionDetails": "¡ La cena está lista!-Iré en un minuto.",
    "answer": "i will come, i am coming",
    "answerDetails": "Dinner is ready!-I will come in a minute."
  },
  {
    "id": 3431,
    "question": "sospecha",
    "questionDetails": "La policía arrestó a la pandilla bajo sospecha de homicidio.",
    "answer": "suspicion",
    "answerDetails": "The police arrested the gang on suspicion of murder."
  },
  {
    "id": 3432,
    "question": "fallar",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes fallar o puedes volar.",
    "answer": "fail",
    "answerDetails": "You may fail or you may fly."
  },
  {
    "id": 3433,
    "question": "funcionó",
    "answer": "Worked"
  },
  {
    "id": 3434,
    "question": "evidente",
    "questionDetails": "Era evidente por sus comentarios en clase que no se había terminado el libro.",
    "answer": "evident, clear, apparent",
    "answerDetails": "It was evident from her comments in class that she hadn’t finished the book."
  },
  {
    "id": 3435,
    "question": "quedarnos",
    "questionDetails": "Quedarnos en la cama todo el día.",
    "answer": "stay",
    "answerDetails": "Stay in bed together all day."
  },
  {
    "id": 3436,
    "question": "llevarla",
    "questionDetails": "Mi hija está enferma. Tengo que llevarla al médico.",
    "answer": "take her",
    "answerDetails": "My daughter is sick. I need to take her to the doctor."
  },
  {
    "id": 3437,
    "question": "análisis",
    "questionDetails": "El análisis de la situación económica de la empresa mostró que necesitaban buscar inversores lo antes posible.",
    "answer": "review, test, exploration",
    "answerDetails": "The review of the company’s financial situation showed that they needed to look for investors as soon as possible."
  },
  {
    "id": 3438,
    "question": "queso",
    "questionDetails": "Tambien por su queso.",
    "answer": "cheese",
    "answerDetails": "Also for their cheese."
  },
  {
    "id": 3439,
    "question": "dejara",
    "questionDetails": "Tu madre me dijo que te dejara en paz.",
    "answer": "leave",
    "answerDetails": "Your mother told me to leave you alone."
  },
  {
    "id": 3440,
    "question": "atentos",
    "questionDetails": "La razón es que tus espíritus están atentos.",
    "answer": "attentive, vigilant, tuned",
    "answerDetails": "The reason is your spirits are attentive."
  },
  {
    "id": 3441,
    "question": "costar",
    "questionDetails": "El viaje le costará £ 25.",
    "answer": "cost",
    "answerDetails": "The journey will cost her £25."
  },
  {
    "id": 3442,
    "question": "quedara",
    "questionDetails": "Quería que se quedara.",
    "answer": "stay, stick around",
    "answerDetails": "I wanted him to stay."
  },
  {
    "id": 3443,
    "question": "salvaje",
    "questionDetails": "Actuando en Hollywood estaba más allá de mis sueños más salvajes.",
    "answer": "wild, savage, feral",
    "answerDetails": "Performing in Hollywood was beyond my wildest dreams."
  },
  {
    "id": 3444,
    "question": "útil",
    "questionDetails": "Aspirinas son útiles para dolores de cabeza.",
    "answer": "useful, helpful, handy",
    "answerDetails": "Aspirins are useful for headaches."
  },
  {
    "id": 3445,
    "question": "disfruta",
    "questionDetails": "Jessica está feliz aquí en el estudio porque disfruta cantando.",
    "answer": "she enjoys",
    "answerDetails": "Jessica is happy here in the studio because she enjoys singing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3446,
    "question": "cumplo",
    "questionDetails": "Yo cumplo mi parte del trato.",
    "answer": "keep",
    "answerDetails": "I keep my end of the deal, old friend."
  },
  {
    "id": 3447,
    "question": "rostro",
    "questionDetails": "La expresión de su rostro lo decía todo.",
    "answer": "face, countenance",
    "answerDetails": "The expression on her face said it all."
  },
  {
    "id": 3448,
    "question": "contamos",
    "questionDetails": "Nos ofrecimos como voluntarios en una escuela primaria ayer. Les contamos chistes a los niños y jugamos con ellos.",
    "answer": "we told",
    "answerDetails": "We volunteered at an elementary school yesterday. We told the kids jokes and played with them."
  },
  {
    "id": 3449,
    "question": "juzgar",
    "questionDetails": "No se puede juzgar sus propios juegos .",
    "answer": "judge",
    "answerDetails": "You can not judge their own games."
  },
  {
    "id": 3450,
    "question": "acercar",
    "questionDetails": "Usted tiene aquí, si se puede acercar una cámara.",
    "answer": "approach",
    "answerDetails": "You have here, if we can approach a camera."
  },
  {
    "id": 3451,
    "question": "extra",
    "questionDetails": "Supongo que puede esperar a tu extra.",
    "answer": "bonus",
    "answerDetails": "I guess it can wait till bonus time."
  },
  {
    "id": 3452,
    "question": "preguntes",
    "questionDetails": "Estaba esperando que lo preguntes.",
    "answer": "ask",
    "answerDetails": "I was waiting for you to ask."
  },
  {
    "id": 3453,
    "question": "comenzó",
    "questionDetails": "Comenzó su carrera de profesor hace 30 años.",
    "answer": "he began, she started",
    "answerDetails": "He began his career as a teacher 30 years ago."
  },
  {
    "id": 3454,
    "question": "fuese",
    "questionDetails": "Puede que no, si fuese un secreto.",
    "answer": "was",
    "answerDetails": "Maybe not if it was a secret."
  },
  {
    "id": 3455,
    "question": "antigua",
    "questionDetails": "Una ciudad justa, y una antigua y gloriosa.",
    "answer": "ancient, old, former",
    "answerDetails": "A fair city, and an ancient and glorious one."
  },
  {
    "id": 3456,
    "question": "entraron",
    "questionDetails": "Y los vecinos entraron el mismo año.",
    "answer": "entered",
    "answerDetails": "And the neighbors entered the same year."
  },
  {
    "id": 3457,
    "question": "cambié",
    "questionDetails": "Lo cambié a marcos.",
    "answer": "changed, switched, swapped",
    "answerDetails": "I have changed it into marks."
  },
  {
    "id": 3458,
    "question": "encarga",
    "questionDetails": "Quién se encarga de garantizar que el sitio mantiene …",
    "answer": "responsible, handles, charge",
    "answerDetails": "Who is responsible for ensuring that the site holds …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3459,
    "question": "fijo",
    "questionDetails": "Gastos fijos.",
    "answer": "fixed, steady",
    "answerDetails": "Fixed expenses."
  },
  {
    "id": 3460,
    "question": "permiten",
    "questionDetails": "Cargas que nos permiten.",
    "answer": "allow, enable, permit",
    "answerDetails": "Burdens that allow us."
  },
  {
    "id": 3461,
    "question": "señales",
    "questionDetails": "Bueno, tienes que aprender sus señales.",
    "answer": "signals, cues, landmarks",
    "answerDetails": "You have to learn their signals."
  },
  {
    "id": 3462,
    "question": "duros",
    "questionDetails": "Se tienen reflejos breves y duros de todo.",
    "answer": "hard, tough, harsh",
    "answerDetails": "You get really short, hard reflections off everything."
  },
  {
    "id": 3463,
    "question": "bolsillo",
    "questionDetails": "Ella lo vio bloquear y el bolsillo de la llave.",
    "answer": "pocket",
    "answerDetails": "She watched him lock up and pocket the key."
  },
  {
    "id": 3464,
    "question": "cuantos",
    "questionDetails": "Lo que necesitas es unos cuantos dias de prision.",
    "answer": "few",
    "answerDetails": "What you need is a few days in prison."
  },
  {
    "id": 3465,
    "question": "decido",
    "questionDetails": "Yo decido si nos quedamos o no.",
    "answer": "decide",
    "answerDetails": "I decide whether we stay or not."
  },
  {
    "id": 3466,
    "question": "horario",
    "questionDetails": "Necesitaremos el horario de trenes para planear nuestro viaje.",
    "answer": "schedule, hours",
    "answerDetails": "We will need the train schedule to plan our trip."
  },
  {
    "id": 3467,
    "question": "vacía",
    "answer": "empty, void, blank"
  },
  {
    "id": 3468,
    "question": "desperté",
    "questionDetails": "Trate de detenerlo y me desperté quince minutos despues.",
    "answer": "woke up, awoke, woke",
    "answerDetails": "I tried to stop him and woke up fifteen minutes later."
  },
  {
    "id": 3469,
    "question": "oscuridad",
    "questionDetails": "La oscuridad de su chaqueta.",
    "answer": "darkness, obscurity, blackness",
    "answerDetails": "The darkness of his jacket."
  },
  {
    "id": 3470,
    "question": "convertirse",
    "answer": "develop, become, converted"
  },
  {
    "id": 3471,
    "question": "apoyar",
    "questionDetails": "No voy a apoyar ninguna estrategia que sea perjudicial para el desarrollo económico.",
    "answer": "endorse",
    "answerDetails": "I’m not going to endorse any strategy that would be detrimental to economic growth."
  },
  {
    "id": 3472,
    "question": "putas",
    "questionDetails": "Tu y tus putas salgan de nuestra propiedad.",
    "answer": "whores, hookers, bitches",
    "answerDetails": "You and your whores get off of our property."
  },
  {
    "id": 3473,
    "question": "agenda",
    "questionDetails": "Intentaré hacerte un hueco, pero tengo la agenda algo justa.",
    "answer": "schedule, calendar",
    "answerDetails": "I’ll try to squeeze you in, but my schedule is pretty tight."
  },
  {
    "id": 3474,
    "question": "mina",
    "questionDetails": "No hay mucho oxígeno en la profunda mina, por eso los trabajadores deben tomar descansos frecuentes.",
    "answer": "mine, pit",
    "answerDetails": "There is not much oxygen in the deep mine, so the workers must take frequent breaks."
  },
  {
    "id": 3475,
    "question": "cómplice",
    "questionDetails": "A Lucy la hallaron culpable de ser una cómplice del delito.",
    "answer": "accessory",
    "answerDetails": "Lucy was found guilty of being an accessory to the crime."
  },
  {
    "id": 3476,
    "question": "alcanzo",
    "questionDetails": "alcanzo el numero uno en las listas.",
    "answer": "reached",
    "answerDetails": "reached number one in the charts."
  },
  {
    "id": 3477,
    "question": "trate",
    "questionDetails": "Trate de no cerrar los ojos.",
    "answer": "try, concerned, treat",
    "answerDetails": "Try not to close your eyes."
  },
  {
    "id": 3478,
    "question": "honesto",
    "questionDetails": "Para ser honesto, esperaba jugar peor.",
    "answer": "honest",
    "answerDetails": "To be honest, I expected to play worse."
  },
  {
    "id": 3479,
    "question": "miel",
    "questionDetails": "La miel la hacen las abejas usando el néctar de las flores.",
    "answer": "honey",
    "answerDetails": "Honey is made by bees using the nectar of flowers."
  },
  {
    "id": 3480,
    "question": "valió",
    "questionDetails": "lo que le valió la reputación",
    "answer": "earned",
    "answerDetails": "which earned him the reputation"
  },
  {
    "id": 3481,
    "question": "lógico",
    "questionDetails": "Porque el único movimiento lógico es dejarle fuera.",
    "answer": "logical",
    "answerDetails": "Because the only logical move is to shut him out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3482,
    "question": "olvídalo",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo muchas ganas de verte en un disfraz de payaso.-Olvídalo. No va a pasar.",
    "answer": "forget it",
    "answerDetails": "I’m looking forward to seeing you in a clown costume.-Forget it. It’s not going to happen."
  },
  {
    "id": 3483,
    "question": "andando",
    "questionDetails": "Iba andando a la escuela.",
    "answer": "walk, ticking",
    "answerDetails": "I had to walk to school."
  },
  {
    "id": 3484,
    "question": "confías",
    "questionDetails": "Sé que no confías en nadie.",
    "answer": "trust, confide",
    "answerDetails": "I know you don’t trust anyone."
  },
  {
    "id": 3485,
    "question": "payaso",
    "questionDetails": "Harvey se hizo el payaso simulando ser un perro.",
    "answer": "clown",
    "answerDetails": "Harvey clowned around pretending to be a dog."
  },
  {
    "id": 3486,
    "question": "retirar",
    "questionDetails": "Se negó a retirar lo dicho, abocando a ambas partes a un callejón sin salida.",
    "answer": "retract",
    "answerDetails": "She refused to retract what she had said, causing an impasse between the two sides."
  },
  {
    "id": 3487,
    "question": "lleguemos",
    "questionDetails": "No hasta que lleguemos allí.",
    "answer": "get",
    "answerDetails": "Not until we get there."
  },
  {
    "id": 3488,
    "question": "acompáñame",
    "questionDetails": "Me voy a almorzar. ¡ Acompáñame!.",
    "answer": "join me",
    "answerDetails": "I’m on my way to get lunch. Join me!."
  },
  {
    "id": 3489,
    "question": "aprovechando",
    "questionDetails": "Te estás aprovechando de esa gente.",
    "answer": "taking advantage, leveraging, benefitting from",
    "answerDetails": "You are taking advantage of these people."
  },
  {
    "id": 3490,
    "question": "dolores",
    "questionDetails": "Reduce los gases y los dolores abdominales.",
    "answer": "pains, aches, sorrows",
    "answerDetails": "It reduce gas and abdominal pains."
  },
  {
    "id": 3491,
    "question": "arreglamos",
    "answer": "Unbreak, fix"
  },
  {
    "id": 3492,
    "question": "conocerla",
    "questionDetails": "Me alegro de conocerla.",
    "answer": "meetyou, know",
    "answerDetails": "So nice to meetyou."
  },
  {
    "id": 3493,
    "question": "sabrá",
    "questionDetails": "Sabrá hablar español después de estudiar en el extranjero.",
    "answer": "she will know",
    "answerDetails": "She will know how to speak Spanish after studying abroad."
  },
  {
    "id": 3494,
    "question": "canal",
    "questionDetails": "El Canal de la Mancha.",
    "answer": "channel",
    "answerDetails": "The (English) Channel."
  },
  {
    "id": 3495,
    "question": "conociendo",
    "questionDetails": "Conociendo a los nuestros.",
    "answer": "knowing, getting acquainted",
    "answerDetails": "Just knowing on our own."
  },
  {
    "id": 3496,
    "question": "barbaridad",
    "answer": "atrocity"
  },
  {
    "id": 3497,
    "question": "casados",
    "questionDetails": "Ambos casados con diferentes personas.",
    "answer": "married, weds",
    "answerDetails": "Both of them married to different people."
  },
  {
    "id": 3498,
    "question": "métete",
    "questionDetails": "Solo métete lo por la garganta.",
    "answer": "shove, get, tuck",
    "answerDetails": "Just shove it down your throat."
  },
  {
    "id": 3499,
    "question": "ventaja",
    "questionDetails": "Sus coches tienen la ventaja sobre sus rivales ‘.",
    "answer": "edge, bonus, perk",
    "answerDetails": "His cars have the edge over his rivals’."
  },
  {
    "id": 3500,
    "question": "tráeme",
    "answer": "Bring"
  }
]